But there is
Hannah Montana mania...
Arrived here
this morning...
- Teenager...
- Hannah Montana.
Role model
to millions of...
Hannah Montana phenomenon.
It's taking over the world.
- At just 14...
- Overnight star...
Billboard pop chart...
She's
an ordinary schoolgirl by day.
And if you put on
a blonde wig,
you suddenly become...
Hannah Montana! Whoo!
She was so perfect
in that spot.
Four words Treasury Secretary
Hannah Montana.
Gotta go!
Good to be home.
Hannah! Hannah! Hannah!
Happy 20th anniversary.
Already getting emotional.
That's me. All right.
I mean, come on, how could it
have been 20 years?
Let's do this.
Wow. Look at this.
It's exactly how it was
when I left it.
Home sweet home,
even the legs table.
I think I had these leggings.
Hannah definitely
had these leggings.
Oh.
I guess these
are what sweet niblets are.
I never asked
what a sweet niblet was.
Don't even try it.
That's a season one joke.
This is so surreal.
It is incredible to be here.
But I think I need to bring out
the one person
who might remember
more about Hannah Montana
than me.
Alex!
Oh, my God,
I've always wanted to do that.
- Look at this.
- You don't even know.
This is insane.
As a fan being here,
this is really a trip,
seeing you in this room.
And it's exactly
how I remember it.
Like, it feels like home again.
I feel like I'm going
to pass out right now,
so I can only imagine
people watching this,
seeing you with your blonde hair
as Hannah Montana, the scarf.
-Oh, it's all about the scarf.
-It is so major.
A capri.
There's just a lot
we got to talk about.
-I'm excited.
-Are you ready?
-Yeah. I'm ready.
-Let's go.
Wow.
-Girl.
-Ooh.
Modern.
We're a long way away from
all that lizard iguana-core.
Did you ever notice
how many lizards
there are
in the Stewart kitchen?
It is so many.
But if you knew my dad,
you would know if he got his way
in decorating a living room,
it would have that many lizards.
Miley, this is incredible.
It has been two decades
since Hannah Montana premiered
and became
a cultural phenomenon.
This show defined
an entire generation,
and it is so special
to be here with you
celebrating
the 20th anniversary.
Why did you decide
this was the right way
to return to Hannah?
What I loved most about
the TV show and being Hannah
was that every everybody
could watch this.
Everybody could have me
in their living room.
And, you know,
if I do a show or a concert,
it's exclusive to those
who can make it.
And this, to me, was the way
that I could really
invite everybody
into this celebration.
But it's really for the fans
that grew up with me,
our kind of moment
of just looking at each other
of how much growth,
how much evolution, and how
much they've really supported
and followed me, you know,
from going from Hannah to Miley.
It wasn't always easy.
It was, you know,
a bit of a turbulent transition
at times.
And this just feels like
a moment of not only reflection
of the show itself,
but more just the longevity
and the loyalty
between me and everyone
that I've grown up with.
How did you even come up
with the idea for a special?
Okay, well, I learned a lot
from Dolly.
And one thing she taught me,
which I love,
is promote something
before it's happening,
because then they can't say no.
So I just started saying
there was
a Hannahversary special.
There was none.
Any Hannah Montana
anniversary plans coming along?
Absolutely.
We're working hard on them.
What are you gonna do?
Just tease us?
-I can't tell you.
-Just tell me one little tease.
You see the bangs.
Are you going
to do something for the fans?
There's like a big
birthday party I'm imagining.
So I am on it.
And then my team
kept calling me, being like,
"What is this Hannahversary?"
Well, it doesn't exist,
but I want it to.
And I feel like if I can
get the fans behind me,
as they always are, and show
how much this is wanted.
And so I just started talking
about a Hannahversary
before Hannahversary
even existed.
I love that so much.
Okay, let's go back
to the very beginning
of how you even got here, right?
What do you think,
from that initial audition,
made you stand out
to Disney?
Well, the charisma, uniqueness,
nerve, and talent, okay?
B mark.
I'm Miley Cyrus
and I'm auditioning
for the role
of Hannah Montana.
Yes, it's your red sweater,
but you gotta admit,
it looks way better
on me than you, and--
That's in two months.
And if you think my sweater
looks way better on you,
why did you give it
to me for Christmas?
Because you're always
borrowing my clothes
and I feel bad
because I never borrow yours
because you have nothing I like.
So I got this for you
so you have something I like
and I can borrow it
and it'll make you feel better.
What made me stand out I think
in my audition
was both my weakness
and my strength.
I had no previous experience
in acting.
I literally was just coming
from Nashville, Tennessee.
I was a little cheerleader.
I was just like honestly trying
to get back home
so nobody like stole my spot
on the cheer team.
And so I think I stood out
because everything that
I was doing was so authentic.
It was so just who I am.
No one ever taught me
how to be that way.
I had no reason to come out
to LA and be confident,
like, I can do this.
Literally no ground to stand on.
But I was just like, I sing,
I dance, I'll wear a blonde wig.
And I...
I didn't want it that bad.
Like I really
kind of want them--
There was a boy I had a crush on
in the sixth grade,
so I was just trying to get back
to him, make him my boo.
I was not like,
if I go home, Mom,
this is gonna break my heart.
I was like, I'd love to get it,
but if I don't,
at least I still get
to date Jeff.
Um, so...
Wherever Jeff is
in the world right now--
I know where he is
because I look
at his Facebook
every now and then.
He knows the Jeff
I'm talking about.
There's two Jeffs in my school.
I got both of them.
Tish.
- Don't mind me.
- Mom.
Just a little play date
over here.
-Oh.
-Okay.
-Look how good.
-This I live for still.
I die. I just have been
in here reminiscing.
Okay.
-Girl.
-No, I know.
This was before Hannah.
I love my little cheerleader
and the cowboy.
I mean, Mile, look how little.
-That is so cute.
-I mean, this was our life.
That is everything.
It means so much,
like, thinking back now,
because we loved
cheering so much.
-Uh-huh.
-And you really, like,
I mean, you had to make
a big decision.
Like, cheerleading
was your life.
I loved it.
And then you had
to decide whether you had
to keep auditioning
or stay behind.
And you said, I'm going for it.
-Look how good.
-I mean, how good is it?
Little Miley.
-You spilled something.
-You.
-No, you. Okay.
-I was thinking you.
- I feel like this...
- I feel like...
-What?
-Oh, Miley!
Good ol' Gary.
I mean, I called him personally.
And I'm going
to let him tell the story.
It's a great story.
We had this little
Hannah Montana script,
right, about an everyday girl
who wants to be,
has a secret identity
as a pop superstar.
And I had this nutty ambition
that we could turn
a fictional pop star
into a real-life superstar.
And I thought,
that's a pretty high bar.
And that's why we cast
for 11 months.
We were down
to the last two people.
And you were
this 12-year-old pistol,
and raw and real
and fresh out of Tennessee.
And you both left.
There was ten people
in the room.
And we took a vote.
Was it a landslide?
That's what I want to know.
I feel like
it was like one and one.
It wasn't a landslide.
I didn't think it would be,
which I like that better.
It was not a landslide.
And people put forth their
arguments.
-Their real opinions.
-And I had made a decision,
and I wrote an email
to the team.
I'm going to read you the email
that I wrote.
And it said, "We pride ourselves
not just on creating
great television,
but on creating stars.
I am ready
to pull the trigger on Miley.
Is she a risk?
Unquestionably."
-True. More than you knew.
-"Is she a potential star?
Absolutely.
And whatever comes
of this decision,
I'm thrilled that all of us
will be able to sit down
over a drink in a few years
and remember this moment
when we decided
to forsake the safe route
for the riskier one
and the greater reward."
That's what you did.
You brought that out of them.
That's what you brought
to the table.
That's why this was successful.
-Thank you, Gary.
-Miley.
-Thank you. Thank you so much.
-Thank you.
-You've changed a lot of lives.
-You have.
-Mine.
-More than just yours.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
So you crushed the audition.
Your whole family
moved from Tennessee.
You guys get to Los Angeles
for this once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity.
Was there
any culture shock at all?
Girl, I got here in a miniskirt
and flip-flops
and never looked back.
Like, not even once.
I mean, my mom can tell you.
There was never
one minute where I got to LA
and was, like, homesick.
Who was the first person you met
from the cast?
I think the first person
I ever met
was Lilly and Oliver,
Mitchel and Emily.
And they were
experienced actors.
So I was just
figuring out how I was going
to kind of like fit into a cast
that they knew exactly
what they were doing.
My friends, aren't they
something?
I thought Mitchell Musso
was really cute.
So I was like, okay.
Bye, Jeff.
It's all about Mitchel now.
So that, I was like, great.
Crush. I'm good. Now I'm set up.
And then with Emily, I had
what felt like a teammate,
because I didn't know
exactly what I was doing.
So it was just like, come here.
And I knew that we were going
to have each other's backs
when it came to our timing,
to our scenes, to rehearsing.
Did you guys do anything
in those early days to bond?
Like, did you go to Disneyland?
We went to Panda Express.
Oh.
That was my favorite.
I did something really gnarly.
My favorite thing
to get at Panda Express
was the white rice
and pour Diet Coke on top.
- What?
- Instead of soy sauce,
I used Diet Coke.
It's a whole thing.
But I was like, Emily!
No wonder she was like,
"Uh, who is this bumpkin
that they cast?"
Miley?
No, I am from the South,
in a way that it's really
hard to describe.
But I just described it
perfectly.
Hello, New York!
Looks like your limo's here.
Yeah.
Can we please talk
about your wig in episode one?
What was going on there?
Okay, girl,
we had a pilot budget.
We were like, we didn't know
if we were ever gonna
make it to air,
so they could only invest
in Hannah Montana so much.
When you looked in the mirror
for the first time
and put that wig on,
what did you feel?
I was Hannah Montana
immediately, and...
I... It just felt normal.
It felt natural.
Hello?
Hey, it's me,
landing in 20 seconds.
Great!
Lilly alert in 18 seconds.
She's your best friend, Miley.
Sooner or later,
you're gonna have to tell her
-you're Hannah Montana.
-I pick later.
I asked the fans
what some of
their favorite moments
from the show were.
So many people wrote in and said
that the Jake and Jesse
love triangle with you
was truly some of their
favorite storylines.
And so today, I wanted
to play you a little scene.
- Okay.
- Are you ready?
-Yeah.
-Okay, let's roll it.
Oh, mud crunkies.
Hi, I can't get
to the phone right now,
but I really, really, really
want to hear
what you have to say,
so please leave me a message.
Um, and I don't care
what length,
because I really,
really, really want to hear
what you have to say.
All right, beep!
Hey, it's me.
-I just wanted to say that--
-I feel kind of bad
-about putting you...
-On such a spot like that.
-The bottom line is...
-No matter what you decide...
I just want you
to be happy.
Are you aware of how much
the world was in love
-with that duo back then?
-Yes.
Okay, so now,
20 years later, Miley.
Yes. Who would I pick?
-Jake or Jessie.
-I think...
I can't, because they're both,
like, out there in the world.
Jake.
Because you know what?
He's always out there saying
really nice things about me
in the press, and I pay
attention.
And Jesse,
I haven't heard a peep.
-So I'm going with Jake.
-Let's go, Jesse.
No, I always, I don't know.
I just love the Jake Ryan
fantasy.
- That is such a good answer.
- Yeah.
I can't even tell you
how many times I have watched
the Hannah Montana movie.
What was your reaction
when the "Hoedown Throwdown"
dance was pitched to you?
Oh, I was all in.
I'm, like, always down.
I'm the hoedown.
That's what's good about me,
is if they'll write it in,
I'm like, oh, cool.
We're poppin', lockin',
polka dottin', let's go.
Would you still remember it
to this day?
Yes.
I just did it with Jamal Sims,
and it came back
like it's riding a bike.
-Roll the clip.
-Roll that clip.
Great, great, great,
great, great, great.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
You got the best
of both worlds right here.
-Oh, my gosh. Mi familia!
-Put me in, coach.
Come on! Wow!
I'm ready.
It's bike.
-Bicycle.
-Boom.
-Let's rock.
-Here we go.
Five, six, seven.
Ho!
Uh-huh. So we got it.
Done. Donezo.
We cannot talk
about Hannah Montana
without talking
about the fashion.
Every girl wanted to be her,
dress like her,
and everyone's dream
was to have that closet.
Yes.
My closet.
When I saw the closet,
I was like,
I'm going to need one of those.
Like, I told Tish, get in here
and get the measurements,
get my racks on wheels.
Like, I'm going to need
this button where you push it
and everything, like,
comes forward, all the bags,
all the shoes,
the rotating where,
like, you might miss something
if it's in the back.
Let's talk a little bit more
about your mom.
I think what people
may not fully know is how
she was so involved
in everything.
So much.
But especially, as you just
mentioned, really when it came
to the fashion,
she had a vision.
Yes.
My mom really had a vision for
Miley even more so than Hannah.
Like, we could
walk into a store,
and we would just
know the difference.
Like, that's very Hannah,
that's very Miley.
Here we go.
You remember Hannah's closet.
We modeled my closet after it.
I do, but I don't
remember ever actually,
like, kind of being
on the set of the closet.
-Really?
-No.
-Okay, well, look at this.
-Okay.
- You're gonna be obsessed.
- I am gonna be obsessed.
Go. It's been a while.
Wow. This is so sick.
-First of all...
-I stole that.
You stole this
out of my real closet.
I did.
This was not
to go into the archives yet.
-Okay.
-And this is one of my favorite.
-Rico.
-It's kind of chic.
- I love it.
- Right?
-So good.
-It's good.
I'm seeing what else
I recognize.
-Oh.
-What else you got?
No bedazzler
was safe in our hands.
At all.
Like, if we could get
some glue on it,
we would stick a stone
to it, okay?
-I was wondering about these.
-Those are original.
-They're original?
-Yeah, those are original.
- They're so good.
- You know what?
I think I didn't want
to wear them.
- I remember.
- Right?
-Yes, you have.
-They were...
They weren't for me.
Oh, don't tell Christopher
Lawrence.
This is original.
Just came out from the catwalk.
-By the way, this is still good.
-Okay, wait, there was a thing.
I could wear this now.
Look how cute.
Honestly, so good.
- Do you remember this?
- Ooh, yes.
Look at you. You look gorgeous.
-This is from the pilot.
-That's from the pilot, yes.
The most iconic episode
where it's the pie
in the face where Lilly finds out
that her best friend,
Miley Stewart,
is Hannah Montana.
Ta-da!
I just never loved these jeans.
Hannah wore these so many times.
-She really did.
-With the zebra...
-Here, this.
-Totally.
-Trauma.
-And the...
I never... Ew. I hated the look.
I know. And the combat boot.
The Docs.
-This was not for me.
-No.
-Look.
-Tish.
When Disney shopped,
when Tish shopped.
That's right.
This I loved.
I don't remember.
This is the opening
of the Hannah movie.
-Oh, my gosh. You're right.
-This is the, yeah.
Yes, yes, yes. This.
This, like, come on.
-It's insane.
-It's perfect.
-I'm obsessed.
-I'd wear it right now.
Okay, by the way, we both need
this in our closet.
-Bad.
-Watch this.
-Oop.
-It's old.
-It's 20 years.
-Give her a break.
-We do need this.
-That's what I'm saying,
because it's like, you would've
forgotten about this dress.
But when it rotates,
you're like, oh, yeah, that.
Okay, that one's not mine.
Actually, that one is mine.
-Is it?
-Yes.
-I don't like this.
-I don't remember that one.
I don't like the bohemian
Hannah.
I do feel like
this one's iconic.
That little skirt
that's from that movie.
This is where
I break Lucas Till's heart.
I love this one.
Oh. Love!
This is when
I get hit in the head
with the volleyball
in the Hannah movie.
Hannah's style had an evolution
as she became more
successful.
It definitely got a little
higher-end.
It got higher-end.
That's a very classy way
to put it.
Okay, there's three wigs
in this room.
One of yours, one of mine,
and one of Dolly's.
- I love it.
- Let's go.
Okay, this was...
Later season, when Hannah
got a bit of a shorter haircut.
-This is when they lost me.
-Honestly.
-We literally quit.
-I know.
It's when, like, we do not
take our inches as a joke.
-These are more us.
-Yes.
By the way,
it's so sick that we say us.
We want to talk
about the difference
in season one
and season four.
- The wig.
- Uh-huh.
- Absolutely.
- Literally, like, I feel
like I should have made merch
that said, "will tour for wigs."
Like, the better the tour went,
the better the wig got.
Oh, another one
of your memory books.
Which one? I know. This is what
I was going to show you.
Tish loves a memory book.
-That dress is major.
-I love it.
-That's what I'm saying.
-I was thinking that.
Look, these are cute
of me and Emily and Mitchel.
Love.
-That is so cute.
-You all were so cute.
Love a headshot.
Honestly?
No, we need to bring back
headshots.
We do. I started doing
yours when you were two.
Oh, I know.
-So cute.
-Original.
-Oh, the Dolly.
-The Dolly fax I love.
I know how
to read it just like her, too.
"Hey, Miley."
That's what she always says.
"Hey, Miley.
When I got those beautiful
flowers,
I didn't realize it was
the 15th anniversary
of Hannah Montana."
That's what she always says.
"I'm so proud of you.
Just know I'm always proud
to be your Aunt Dolly,
whether it's on Hannah Montana
or at Thompson Station."
-Hilarious.
-I love you, Aunt Dolly.
So good.
Sitting here is so crazy for me,
because you were, like,
eleven when we did the pilot.
- I know.
- Eleven.
-I know.
-It was just, like, so crazy
to think about really picking up
our lives and moving.
-Yeah.
-But looking back on it,
it honestly was just
the most magical thing ever.
Well, Tish, you really,
it'll make me so emotional
because I feel like every time
people, they meet me
and they see who I am
and they see that,
like, I know what's important
to me in this life.
And I love being Hannah,
I love being Miley Cyrus,
I love my personas,
but what I'm most proud
of is who I am
as a person.
You've just always
really taught me to kind of,
like, be in the moment,
be authentic to who you are,
and you've never...
You never tried
to keep me Hannah.
You wanted Miley to express
herself,
even if that
meant losing all of this.
-Yeah.
-You know, so it was always,
you really taught me
how to be who I am.
And that's because of my mommy.
I love you so much.
That era of Disney Channel
was really so formative
for so many of us.
-We had Raven-Symoné.
-Yes.
- We had the Sprouse twins.
- Yes.
We had Selena Gomez.
We had Demi Lovato.
We had the cast
of High School Musical.
Yes.
What was it like for you to be
at the center of that moment?
She has the name.
The-- New Jersey,
-Nebraska, Arizona--
-Montana!
Okay, so one of my favorite
memories is we all went
to New York to do promotion.
And it was right as
High School Musical came out.
So Vanessa and Zac
were like, so famous.
And they were
the coolest kids ever.
High School Musical was so big.
And they were boyfriend,
girlfriend.
And they were everything.
And they loved me because I was
mature for my age.
So then they were like, hey,
like when we're doing press,
we could like pick you up
if you want. I was like, yeah.
So then they picked me up and I
got to go in like a black car
with Vanessa and Zac
and roll up to the upfronts.
And that was like a prime time
of like Disney and those shows.
They were so beyond kids.
Like everyone knew
like Vanessa
and Zac and High School Musical.
Like Disney wasn't just
for kids right then.
What Disney boy
did you have the biggest crush
on at the time?
Hmm.
The Disney boy that I had
the biggest crush on.
My crush for Zac grew.
High School Musical Zac
is not the one I want.
I like ripped, a little older.
I secretly, okay,
Dylan Sprouse was my boyfriend.
I think he was the cutest.
Wait, you actually
dated him?
Yeah,
that was my boyfriend.
- Did we know?
- I don't know.
I think maybe it was rumored,
but it's true.
Confirmed.
Thank you
for confirming that for us.
Dylan was my crush.
Their dad would take us
to sushi.
I was into the whole culture.
And it was a two for one.
Like, bring the brother.
Hello.
Obviously, being Disney royalty,
I have to ask, what was
the coolest perk you got
to experience at that time?
Ooh, the coolest perk.
I'm a Disney legend now, and I
have Disney legend parking,
and it says
"Disney legend" when I park.
That is clutch.
You roll up, you're like, hello.
It says Disney legend,
and I pull in.
Do you smile every time?
I take the pic, and I send it
to everyone I know, like,
don't forget, don't forget.
Don't forget
who you're talking to.
Like, anyone tries
to tell me anything,
it's just, like,
Disney legend parking.
It doesn't matter where I am,
like, any restaurant,
but excuse me, where's
your Disney legend parking?
They're like, babe,
this is not the--
Like, yeah, relax.
You're at the Beverly Hilton,
just chill.
I know, but where's
the legends-only parking?
Oh, my God, that is...
I love the Disney legend
parking.
-I can tell.
-I love...
-That's my favorite part.
-That's incredible.
Can you explain to me,
how did Taylor Swift end up
in the Hannah Montana movie?
Okay, so for that scene...
Get the tea kettle.
That scene, they were looking
for...
My girl's like that one.
Tish just back there
with the lawyer.
Okay, so the way
that Taylor Swift ended up
in the Hannah Montana movie was
because this was kind
of the beginning of her career,
and they were looking
for someone that
would authentically, no shade,
I guess, be performing
in a barn.
We both performed in the barn.
And so she came into the
performance,
and she had
written a song
for Hannah Montana,
maybe even two.
But she actually
wrote the finale song,
"You'll Always
Find Your Way Back Home."
Credit where credit's due.
-That song.
-Banger.
- Whoa.
- Stands the test of time.
She ate with that one.
- Down.
- She ate down.
- Wait.
- Hi!
- Wait, what the hell?
- Mikayla red.
This is so crazy.
- No, everything is identical.
- Do you feel weird?
-Hopefully, me, too.
-How do you feel?
- Excited that you're here.
- Oh, my God.
- Come in.
- 20 years.
You would have never been
in this living room, right?
Well, I went on set, twice.
Just only on the set,
not for actual scenes.
No.
Because you were more
of like a Hannah's life.
I was a Hannah's life.
Honestly, I thought that this
would overwhelm me more,
and that I would feel super
emotional and not be able
to control the tears. But it's
actually just been really fun.
- That's so cool.
- I know.
- I weirdly, miss it.
- This is so wild.
What do you
remember about filming?
Because there's so much
of it that was a blur.
I remember being
in that blue, weird makeup.
-Where we were like aliens?
-Yes.
Johnny?
-Wait, he's not out here.
-Huh. Too bad.
See you, sucker.
I remember feeling ugly in that.
Oh, definitely.
Because we're like, 15,
and I want to feel pretty,
and I'm like, ugh.
When I watch it back,
like, they were vicious.
It's pretty mean.
-Has been.
-Never was.
-Bottle blonde.
-Lip-syncer.
Bra-stuffer.
-I hate you.
-Like I care.
I don't think they would get away
with saying half of that stuff.
-Absolutely not.
-I was so mean. I'm sorry.
-We can make amends now.
-Yes.
Do you want to see something
that I think
you're going to love?
-Yeah. Okay.
-Okay. Come over here.
I got you, this is a gift,
and it actually works great
with your red sweater.
You came Mikayla red.
Yes!
Wait, it's my bun
that's in the way.
-Look at me. I'm back.
-It looks very cute.
Miss Chanel, it's very that.
You know what?
I'm not mad at it.
-It's perfect. That's for you.
-This is so amazing.
-I love you, girl.
-Thanks for coming, Selena.
-Thank you.
-You're the best.
You are.
And you're killing it.
You look great.
Thank you. And I have
a performance after this.
I'm doing "This is the Life"
and "The Climb."
"This is the Life" was
the first song I ever did
- as Hannah Montana.
- Really?
Now to perform it
with everybody knowing
and singing along
is really sweet.
That's really cute.
I had the whole Meet Miley album
was like, my life.
-You created culture, babe.
-You too.
- All right, kill it.
- Let's go, Mikayla.
- Very cute.
- Thanks, girl.
It's really sweet
to know somebody for like, 20 years.
That means I've
known you almost 20 years.
- That's weird.
- That is really weird.
I wanna hear you singing it.
Thank you guys
for being here so much.
You know, I thought a lot about
the 20th anniversary,
the "Hannahversary."
I get so mad when
people call it an anniversary.
It's not just any anniversary.
But it's just so much fun
to celebrate and not only
to look back, but also be
in the present moment, look out
and see that everybody
else has grown up too.
We all look fabulous.
And I also love
that so many new faces,
so many young people that
are just discovering the show
for the first time,
now, it's just such an amazing
celebration of truly what
Hannah always did, which was,
bring people together.
And now, what I love is that
I used to think of Hannah
as something separate of myself.
I would think of,
as a character, even though it was me,
I always would think
what would be best for Hannah.
And I didn't always think about
that as if we were integrated.
And what I'm loving
about this special
is that it's my kind
of reclaiming
of merging Hannah
and Miley together.
I like some of what
Hannah's got going,
but I also, you know,
I like a lot of Miley.
So, I want to put them together.
I hear heels,
and they're not mine.
-Hi.
-Hi, O-M-G.
You're more Hannah than me.
Look! We match.
We do match.
It's so good to hug you.
Okay, I have to show you
something really sickening
- Show me.
- Okay.
Well, it melted my heart,
made me so excited to know
that you grew up
watching Hannah.
You literally walked so I could run.
Like, what I do on stage,
where I can, like, go
on a red carpet and just be...
Oh, I was gagged for that.
But that's because, like,
you took a lot of the heat
for that in 2012, 2013, like...
-That means a lot to me.
-Like, I don't have to deal
with that as much, because,
like, you really...
Like, the world
took it out on you.
Like, to see you be
the artist you are,
to be able to do this,
it just shows,
like, your heart and,
like, your appreciation
for your younger self
and, like, what got you here.
That's what really this whole moment,
this celebration is about is,
loving on our younger self,
knowing that, like,
my younger me worked so hard
so, I could have
the life that I have now and...
For me, it was
always really fun.
And that's why the outfits,
the stage, like,
I mean, literally, the reason
that the Jonas Brothers were on tour
with me, was because,
Nick was my boyfriend,
and I wanted
to not leave my boyfriend.
So I'd be like, okay, I'll go on
tour if my boyfriend can come.
And they were like, cute,
have your boyfriend open for the show.
Boom.
Like, I was always just like,
well, it'll be more fun
if Nick is there.
It'll be more fun, Nick, name
drop, like, first name basis.
And so we always put me...
My mom, like, really advocated
for me to always be around other kids.
That's so good. It's so hard.
-It was so fun.
-How does it feel like...
to put back on the wig?
Is there any type of, like...
It's just little clip-ins.
-This is all me.
-That's you?
-Yes!
-What?
I just have in a little piece.
-Wait, what?
-Yeah, I went Hannah.
-With the bang and everything.
-The bang. This is me.
I'm so grateful that
I get to be a part of this.
I mean, I grew up
watching Hannah
at my grandparents' house,
like...
And it just means so much.
I'm so grateful for you.
Thank you so much.
You're everything.
Thank you.
Don't take any other clothes.
They gotta go back to the archives.
-Don't you worry.
-I feel like
you're gonna walk
out in that tutu in a second.
I may take that bolero.
That's what I was thinking.
The bolero's very you.
How do you think
Hannah Montana
shaped your family's life
as a whole?
I don't know if our reality
would be the same without the show,
um, for better or for worse.
No family really gets
to experience what we had.
Yeah, there is obviously
so much history
from working on set
with your dad
for so many years,
and he's here today.
With a fresh hairdo thanks to...
...moi.
How are you feeling?
I'm really excited
for him to be here,
because I know how much
our relationship means
to everyone that
watched this show.
I think when me and my dad are
good, people, they feel better.
It just feels good when
the Cyruses are getting along.
He is so cute.
Honey, at your age, there's only
two things that are cute.
That's squirrels
and little puppy dogs.
So, uh, any idea how you're
gonna get yourself out of this one?
Daddy, that's your job.
You're a dad.
That's what you do.
Thank you so much, Daddy.
I love you, Mile.
I love you, too.
-Hey.
I thought you changed the locks.
- Hi, Dad.
- How's it going?
- Welcome home.
- Look at this.
This is amazing.
You'll never believe I said
the exact same thing
-when I walked in here.
-Really?
I walked into this living room
and said, "Home sweet home."
Home sweet home.
You're never going to believe
every detail is as it was,
except you and me.
- Welcome home.
- Right?
So what do you feel
being back in the set?
I mean, I felt immediately
like it was just...
we could start calling "action"
on another episode and it would be normal.
Is it too late
for me to learn my lines
from my previous?
This show wasn't written for us,
even though in some way
it feels like it was.
It was just so perfect.
But what do you remember
from auditioning together?
The guy that was
auditioning
for the dad before me
was doing his thing,
and I'm sitting there going,
"That guy's great.
That guy's great." I'm going,
"Man, that's the dad. That's the dad."
So, when he left the room,
I walked into the room and said,
"Guys, that's the dad
that just walked out."
Me and mom were both like,
"Shut up. Shut up."
You were always the guy trying
to give the other guy the job.
Well, I'm glad you were the dad.
Couldn't change it
if I tried to.
This was meant for us.
We went and did our handshake.
-We sang together.
-The ha...
-Can you still do the handshake?
-I only remember this part.
-Do you remember?
-We got to be standing, right?
Well, I can't remember
after this.
Let's try it. I can't either.
It's something like...
- Uh-oh.
- And then...
Dad, I don't remember.
And then...
And then something like this.
And then like...
National champions!
Dad, this was rough.
- But it's pretty close.
- It's pretty close.
We did the handshake,
we did our songs,
and we ran some scenes.
I never thought about the show,
like, whether it was
successful or not.
That was never a conversation.
I get asked that a lot,
if you and I knew
how successful the show was.
It wasn't why we did it.
Yeah, it just kind of seemed
like our lives, didn't it?
It was art imitating life,
imitating art.
and you were always Miley to me,
and it was that realism
of you being both
that I think was the connection
to the world.
It was one of
the funnest things in my life,
being part of this show.
Me too.
All right, Dad, what would you
think about doing a read-through,
running our lines
together one time?
Let me think about it.
No, I'm just kidding.
Let's go.
Let's do it. Come on.
-All right.
This is like the table where
all the Stewarts had to talk.
Honestly, it feels like
we should have
a couple bowls of cereal.
That's it. All right.
Let's look at our scripts.
-Oh, God.
-"I'll Always Remember You."
I don't remember it at all.
Oh, I do.
You've had yourself
quite a day, haven't you?
I seem to be having more
and more of them lately.
Look at me.
Being two people seemed like
such a great idea back then.
That's because...
It was a great idea.
It gave you a chance to kind
of...
I know.
Live a normal life.
It doesn't seem to be doing
a bang-up job of that anymore.
Darling, nothing works forever.
It's like my mullet.
A thing of beauty
in its day, but...
Tell you what, sooner or later,
even the party
in the back has to end.
Are you telling me it's time
to give up Hannah?
Oh, I would never say that.
And neither would Lilly or Jesse.
The only one
who can tell you that is...
Oh, no.
Please don't say,
"Listen to my heart."
Darling, it's just...
Or my kidney, or my spleen...
Or any other vital organ.
-Yeah, that's my favorite line.
-That was kind of good.
What do you want me to tell you?
I want you to tell me
that if I give up the secret,
everything's going to be
all right.
Oh, I can't do that.
But here's what I can tell you.
You'll be able
to go to that school with Lilly.
to go out with Jesse
without half the world
hating him.
You will have
to give up your privacy.
No matter where you go,
people are always
going to recognize you.
And, they're going
to treat you different.
Is it worth it?
Only you can decide that.
I should have listened
to my spleen.
I love that line, too,
by the way.
Sweet niblet.
If the scene is running dry,
you throw in a sweet niblet
and everyone was gonna laugh.
- Every time.
- I thought that was fun.
-That was great.
-Thanks for being here, Dad.
Anytime, bud.
-Love you.
It's the best of both worlds.
Let's go.
-Get out.
-When should I follow?
-This way?
- Yes.
- Okay.
Look, we can use
the old patio door.
Come on, let's go.
One last time.
Oh, there's Jason out there
having a puff.
- Speaking of bud.
- There he is.
Oh, we forgot to close the door.
Mosquitoes are coming in.
We're celebrating today,
and it's emotional, right?
Because we're sitting here,
and it's...
kind of closing
a chapter in a way.
What would you want to go back
and say to younger Miley?
For younger Miley,
I think what I would want
to say is I'm proud of myself.
I really did have
a vision for my life.
It was about...
how my spirit felt
when I was making people laugh.
Even, like, these silly things
that we used to do on the set,
like, fall down the stairs
or look ridiculous
in front of a boy. Like,
I love looking out
and seeing people laugh at me.
Howdy, cuz.
Look, I'm a cup fly.
Daddy, who put my face
on that zit?
Neck is cramping,
and this wig is really heavy!
I just want to tell
all the kids out there
that Hannah Montana
thinks carrots are great!
Hey, Miley. Do you know what
this thing does?
I think I got
a pretty good idea.
I'm just gonna... Bam!
Hi, everybody.
Right, this is
getting ridiculous.
And so, I think that my younger
self, if I could say anything,
is that I'm proud
that that's always stayed true,
that what I've done has always
come from a heart first.
It's always been about making
the world a better place
from what I can offer.
And...
You know, whether
that's being laughed at,
whether that's having
someone sing along to a song I've written,
I just am proud
that I make people feel less
alone
by sharing and kind of...
being brave enough to wear
my heart on my sleeve and let people in.
Last question.
What would you say to your fans
who have been by your side
for the past 20 years?
Something I would say
to the fans,
which is not just because it's
the 20th anniversary of Hannah Montana,
it's the deepest thank you,
because my life is so beautiful,
and it hurts and pains me
to know that
not every pop star's experience
is the one that I get to have.
But there is a piece
of my life that is very...
It's really unique to me,
and sometimes I...
Sometimes I can feel lonely
in this experience
because not everybody...
There's no one I can really sit
with that I can say,
"This is what my life is like."
But that's where...
That's where, like...
And I think
the reason I'm so emotional is
because as I get older,
my dad gets older,
my mom, she gets older.
So many of the people that
have paved the path for me
to feel like I have a safety
in this lifestyle.
Um...
I've been extremely blessed
to have so much love
within my family.
And now...
finding love in a different way,
finding love...
to where I feel like,
I'm taking the next step into my womanhood
of like creating a life
with someone.
I think that's, I mean
everybody has I think a fantasy
of wanting to feel loved
and I've always felt it
from these different places.
Especially,
from the millions of people
that, you know,
they hold up
"I love you" signs at concerts
or write it in the comments.
But, to experience it now
and imagining what my next
20 years might look like,
is going to be so different
than it did on a TV show.
But again, so much of it
will hopefully be the same.
The jokes, the wisdom,
the quality time in the kitchen,
the ending the day
by sitting on a couch and writing a song.
But the only difference is that,
you know, it'll be mine.
It'll be just for me.
It won't be broadcasted
across the world.
You have something special
for the fans, planned,
to close out this chapter.
So, I will let you
take it from here.
Let's do it.
-Thank you.
-This is so emotional.
-I love you.
-Get ready to really cry.
- I love you.
- Let's go.
Felt great and fun.
- It's fun.
- Yeah.
I think people, if you
will let some of this stay in.
Let's go.
It's been an honor
to celebrate 20 years of Hannah Montana.
And I've looked back
at every memory with a heart full of love.
Hannah, she gave me my start,
but my fans gave me this life.
There's the purity ring.
Oh, my God!
- Work!
- Oh, my God.
Noah!
Thank you.
We were talking earlier
about how, like,
whenever there needed to be
a little girl in the scene,
we would just always sacrifice Noah.
We were like,
"Noah's available."
Oh, my God. I was always around
'cause I loved the set so much.
- Yeah.
- Like, I had so much fun on set.
I played so many little girls
- with so many different moms.
- I know, right?
Like, it was insane.
Well, happy 20th
anniversary, Miss Montana.
Thank you, Noey.
-It was a lot of fun.
-I love you.
Thank you, thank you.
You're the best.
-I love you so much.
-I love you girls.
-I love you.
-Love you, Mom, I'm literally so proud.
I loved being Hannah then...
I'm so living for it now.
This is Miley.
This is Hannah.
- This is Hannah.
- That's a combo.
In Nashville,
we don't say "birth-day."
We say, "burdday"
Like, "It's my burdday"
This is my purse for today.
-I... Okay, well...
-It can't go in the archives
until I'm done using it.
I was literally pie-ing for my life
at that moment.
I was like,
"Girl, you gotta slam that pie good!
You wanna get renewed!"
Can I wear the wig?
I was thinking you might want
to wear the wig.
And they're like, "Tish was right."
Tish was right. Tish is always right.
-She is.
-She's gonna love that.